♪If I am gone from this world,
will the dark night collapse?♪
♪If I never return
to guard by your side♪
♪If I seal away our encounter
and erase all trace♪
♪Like endless snow
falling into the deep sea♪
♪This life is but a fleeting illusion,
yet it gave me courage♪
♪Love is a miracle♪
=Spring Over Phoenix Pond=
(Adapted from Qin An'an's
"Spring Over Phoenix Pond")
=Episode 15=
Fangyun?
Yun.
What is it?
Why are you back?
Wasn't this Zhen's idea?
What do you mean?
Didn't you tell me to come back?
(Qi Fangyun, Qi Yuan's aunt)
I mourned for Second Young Master Zhou
for half a year.
Who knew
that yesterday, Grand Preceptor Zhou
suddenly forced me to take
my own life to die with my husband
in exchange for the Zhou family's
chastity plaque.
So I quickly had my dowry maid send word
to ask my parents for help.
She brought back Zhen's letter.
The letter said
that I should take medicine
and fake my death
and find a chance to escape.
Zhen's plan really worked.
I finally got out.
What letter?
I never got any letter.
This...
Aunt.
Where is your dowry maid now?
Lian'er didn't come back?
Oh no.
She was probably bought off
by Grand Preceptor Zhou.
Once the chastity plaque is granted,
the Qi family will be charged
with deceiving the Emperor.
Your Lordship,
Grand Preceptor Zhou
has brought people in.
What?
Qi Fangyun,
here you are.
Marquis Yongping,
you joined forces with Qi Fangyun
to fake her death
and cheat the court
out of a chastity plaque.
The evidence is conclusive.
The Emperor has issued an order.
All the Qi family are
to be taken to prison.
Grand Preceptor Zhou,
what plaque?
I don't know anything about it.
Yuan,
don't be reckless.
Let's speak before the Emperor
and argue our case then.
Are you going to defy the imperial order?
If you anger His Majesty,
you'll drag everyone
in the Qi family down
with you.
Qi Yuan.
Let go.
Do you want to die?
The rest of us don't want to die.
Shut up.
Where is Qi Yuan?
Any word on her?
Your Highness,
what do we do?
His Majesty is furious.
At noon tomorrow,
the Qi family will be beheaded in public.
Miss Qi is also wanted.
Noon is almost here.
Take them to the execution ground.
Go.
It's all Qi Yuan's fault.
She ruined our whole family.
How did I give birth to such a disaster?
Mother.
We treated her like family,
but she never once put us
in her heart.
I don't want to die.
Zhao.
I don't want to die, Mother.
Grand Preceptor Zhou.
Grand Preceptor,
something has happened
to the Zhou family.
(Chastity)
Everyone,
the women on the Zhou family's
chastity plaque last night
appeared to me in a dream.
They said
they were framed by generations
of the Zhou family heads.
They were deeply wronged.
Their deaths
were all for this plaque
to preserve the Zhou family's honor.
Nonsense!
I'm talking nonsense?
Grand Preceptor Zhou's younger sister,
Zhou Yingyue.
You...
She had not yet married
when her husband died first.
Grand Preceptor Zhou
forced his own younger sister
to marry a memorial tablet.
On the night of the wedding,
his sister hanged herself.
Grand Preceptor Zhou
spread the word everywhere
that his sister
was so steadfast and chaste,
and used that
to get this chastity plaque.
The Zhou family became famous,
and he used the chance
to rise in rank and fortune.
But no one knew
that he had strangled
his own sister to death.
Strangled to death?
How outrageous.
How cruel.
I can't believe
Grand Preceptor Zhou would do that.
That's a baseless accusation.
How dare you slander
an imperial official?
If your sister truly died
in self-sacrifice for her husband,
why would the memorial tablet
worshipped by the Zhou family
have a soul-suppressing formation
laid into it,
with your sister's
and the other women's birth dates
carved into it?
Everyone, look.
These are the birth dates
of the women suppressed by the Zhou family
at the Guanyin Temple
in the west of the city.
Zhou Yingyue.
Hour of Jichou, Day of Xinyou,
Month of Gengwu, Year of Jimao.
Zhou Jingshu,
Qin of Zhou family,
Lin of Zhou family.
(Zhou Yingyue, Zhou Jingshu)
These names and birth dates
match
those on the plaque.
The names and birth dates
on the chastity plaque
are there for everyone to see.
It must be you
who copied the words from the plaque
onto the yellow paper
to frame the Zhou family.
Is that not so?
If she copied it,
then Grand Preceptor Zhou
would be wrongly accused.
You say that's fake?
What about your daughter-in-law,
Qi Fangyun?
The Zhou family's eldest son, Zhou Ping,
was a regular at Yueying Pleasure House.
He died of the pox.
The pox?
Grand Preceptor Zhou,
your son was a lecher.
He got what he deserved.
And yet you forced his wife
to die in chastity for him.
In this world,
what kind of heartless logic is that?
Exactly. How can that be?
That's right.
There's no such thing.
Prince Jing,
you can't just believe that woman.
That's only her one-sided story.
This was dug up from your son's grave.
It's his personal belongings.
If he didn't die of the pox,
you can pick this up
and show everyone.
- Pick it up.
- Go on, pick it up.
Did everyone hear that?
His son was exactly that kind of man.
And yet he still wants to force
his innocent daughter-in-law to die.
He's using our women's lives
to prop up the Zhou family's reputation.
- Exactly.
There's no such thing.
Shameless scoundrel.
So shameless.
What's carved on that chastity plaque
is not some great virtue
but a living, breathing life.
They are daughters,
sisters,
and mothers.
They were bound
by these heartless old rules
and forced by the cold-blooded Zhou family.
They gave their lives,
only to win the Zhou family
a hollow reputation.
Today,
I want to ask for them
and for all women.
Why must a woman's name
only be written on a stone tablet?
Why should men
rise to power and enter officialdom
by stepping on them?
Why?
Exactly. Why?
Why is that?
- Why?
Smash it.
- Smash it.
Don't smash it.
(Die in chastity after their husband dies.
A model of virtue.)
By imperial decree,
the Zhou family forced
the death of their own kin.
Their title is revoked,
and they are punished.
Also,
from this day on,
anyone who trades chastity
for rank or salary
is forever forbidden by law.
Grand Preceptor Zhou
was my only support in court.
And you still couldn't catch Qi Yuan?
What good are you?
I almost had Qi Yuan.
Almost?
What's the use of saying that now?
I don't even have
a single useful man left under me.
Don't we still have Prince Cheng?
What use is a prince
with no real power?
You're right.
Frequent guests at Yueying Pleasure House
weren't only those men
from the Court of Judicial Review.
Your Highness,
Prince Cheng is nothing
but a wolf in fine clothes.
He's tortured more
than ten princess consorts to death.
And you think
No.
where did all his wives
come from?
No.
Take her away.
Your Highness, no!
Go.
- Your Highness, no!
- Go.
Your Highness!
Qi Yuan.
I meant to spare your life.
But you...
(Marquis Yongping Residence)
Thank you for helping me today,
Your Highness.
But our cooperation is over.
Prince Qi is still here.
How can it be over?
Then let's each go our own way.
What if I refuse?
If you know something is wrong,
you should hold your horse.
Xiao Yunting,
listen.
You still owe me
from our previous life.
(What did I owe her in my last life?)
(Could it be)
(that I wronged her?)
♪How I wish to hold onto
this fleeting warmth♪
♪How I wish to live this life
only for you♪
♪When memories sink
and the heart settles♪
♪Forgetting life, death,
parting, and reunion♪
♪How I wish to stay
only in the moment with you♪
♪Anchoring myself by your side♪